April 6th
それ…
Is that...?
Yes, it's what you think it is.
うん　ご名答
Heart-Under-Blade's arms are inside.
ハートアンダーブレードの両腕が入っている
I see.
…そうか
Hmm?
うん？　ああ　阿良々木くんの言いたいことは分かるよ
Ah. I get what you want to say.
あのギロチンカッターがよく約束を守ったなってことだろう
"I'm surprised that Guillotine-Cutter fellow actually held up his end of the bargain", right?
That's quite a grudge you got there.
随分と出し渋ったぜ
Well, it's understandable.
そりゃそうだろうな
In Guillotine-Cutter's defence, though,
ギロチンカッターの場合は他の二人と違って使命でやってるんだからさ
unlike the other two, he does this out of a sense of duty.
Well, at any rate, now you've retrieved all of the limbs.
ともかく　これで四肢をすべて収集したわけだね
Congratulations, Araragi.
おめでとう　阿良々木くん
Whoa there, Araragi.
おいおい　阿良々木くん
おめでとうって言ってるのに　随分と不機嫌な面をしてるじゃないか
I'm congratulating you.
What's with the displeasure written all over your face?
However the means,
何であれ目的を達成したら喜ぶもんだぜ
the completion of one's objectives should be a matter of pleasure.
But you, on the other hand, are emitting an aura one might find at a wake.
それはまるで何だかお通夜みたいなオーラを醸し出してるじゃないか
There's something I don't quite get,
疑問があるんだよ　忍野
Oshino.
ギロチンカッター　それにドラマツルギーもエピソードもそうだ
Guillotine-Cutter,
not to mention
Dramaturgy and Episode,
あいつらはそれぞれキスショットから両腕と右足と左足を奪っている
together they
made away with Kiss-shot's arms and legs.
その割には精々妹と取っ組み合いの喧嘩をしたことがある程度の僕に
But going up against them was me,
a guy whose entire combat experience can be chalked up to tussling with his little sisters.
If you look at it objectively, my defeat was all but inevitable.
結果から見ればあっさりと負けている
So how the hell
これって一体どういうことなんだ
did it end up like this?
Were they just overly weak,
連中が弱いのか　それとも僕が強過ぎるのか
or was I...
just overwhelmingly powerful?
The answer's both.
その両方だね
From their point of view, you appeared insurmountably strong.
連中から見れば阿良々木くんはやはり強過ぎるし
And from your point of view they were, of course, underwhelming pushovers.
阿良々木くんから見れば連中はやはり弱過ぎるんだ
Because after all,
だって君は他の誰でもない
the infamous, the one and only
Kiss-shot Acerola-Orion Heart-Under-Blade
キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードの眷属なのだから
has but a single kin.
いや　だけどその理由だけじゃ…
But that can't be the only reason—
That is the reason.
その理由だけなんだよ
I'm trying to say that if that is the reason, it doesn't make any sense!
だとしたらおかしいだろって言ってんだよ
If you look at it under those assumptions,
それを前提として考えた時　話がおかしくなってしまう
it doesn't add up.
Flashback
If I achieved so much as her kin,
眷属の僕でさえこうなんだ
then she herself operating at full power,
Annihilation
キスショットのフルパワーモードなら
even if they were working together,
あいつら三人がかりでも　全く敵わないはずなんじゃないのか
Annihilation
should've been able to mop the floor with them.
But what if I were to tell you that at that time
その時のハートアンダーブレードがフルパワーでなかったのなら…
Heart-Under-Blade wasn't operating at full power?
That changes things, does it not?
話は別だろう
Well I was planning on giving it to you whether you probed me or not,
まあ　聞かれても聞かれなくても渡すつもりでいたけど
but I'm glad you did ask.
聞かれて渡す方が話の流れがよくて助かるよ　阿良々木くん
The conversation flows much more smoothly this way.
Araragi.
You're quite perceptive, every now and then.
君も偶には鋭いところを見せるじゃないか
This is the heart of Kiss-shot Acerola-Orion Heart-Under-Blade.
キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードの心臓だ
She was not in possession of that heart
その心臓なしで　彼女は吸血鬼退治の専門家と戦ったというわけだ
when she did battle with those vampire hunters.
Given that fact, it wasn't all that improbable that she lost her limbs.
そりゃ四肢を引きちぎられたって分からなくもないさ
気付いてないよな　あいつ
She doesn't know,
does she?
Probably not.
だろうね　彼女は手足を奪われただけだと思っている
She only thinks she lost her extremities.
I see.
そうか…そうだったのか
So that's how it went.
I thought he was one sly bastard,
狡いやつだと思ってたけれど
that Guillotine-Cutter.
ギロチンカッターのやつ　こっそりとキスショットの心臓も奪っていたとはな
But I never would have guessed he snatched out her heart as well.
Nah, that ain't it, Araragi.
いやいや　阿良々木くん
The one who stole her heart
心臓を奪ったのはギロチンカッターじゃないよ
wasn't Guillotine-Cutter.
じゃあ誰だよ
Then who did?
僕
Me.
I took great care
気付かれないようにこっそりと心臓を抜いた
in stealthily extracting her heart.
You're...
お前に…そんなことできるのか
Capable of such a feat?
Sure am.
できるよ
So that means,
ってことは　手足を取り戻しただけじゃ
even if she got all her limbs back,
Kiss-shot couldn't regain
キスショットはフルパワーの完全体には戻れないってことなんだな
her full strength, right?
Yeah, that's right.
そりゃそうだ
So you were
だから君はこの後僕から心臓を取り戻さなきゃいけないはずだった
meant to have to take back her heart from me after all that.
You were to fight me as your fourth opponent.
四戦目としての僕と阿良々木くんの戦い
And, in doing so, an equilibrium would have been struck.
それでこそ　バランスが取れるはずだった
お…お前と…戦うってのか
You!?
Fight you?
Meant to, yes.
はずだった…だよ
But I'm not inclined to anymore.
もうそのつもりはないよ
I mean, I've already given you back the heart.
ほら　既に返してあげたろう
I'm really sorry
委員長ちゃんの件　本当に悪かったね
about what happened to your Class Prez.
It's quite rare that an ordinary person would get involved
一般人がここまで物事に絡んでくるケースっていうのは本当に珍しいんだよ
in a case to such an extent.
Normally, people run away from oddities.
普通は人は怪異から逃げるものだから
That girl actually has a bit of a grasp on the real situation, doesn't she?
あの子は少し常軌を逸しているよね
And with that,
これで
all the parts that Kiss-shot Acerola-Orion Heart-Under-Blade had lost
キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードが失っていたパーツは
すべて取り戻した
have been reclaimed.
That is to say, now you can become human again.
つまりこれで君は人間に戻れるというわけだ
Let me congratulate you once again.
もう一度　おめでとうと言わせてもらうよ
Feel free to rejoice.
喜んでいいんだぜ
Ah, that reminds me.
ああそうそう　これはただの興味から聞くんだけど
This is just out of curiosity,
but have you had any hunger pangs recently?
最近　お腹空かない？
Uh, no.
うん？　いや　前にも言ったと思うけれど
I think I mentioned this before,
吸血鬼になって以来　不死力ってことなのか
but ever since I became a vampire and acquired immortality,
I haven't had much of an appetite at all.
食欲はあんまりないんだよな
That may be,
まあ　でもさすがにそろそろお腹も空いてくる頃だろうと思うよ
but sooner or later I think you'll get hungry.
It has been two weeks, after all.
何せ　もう二週間になるもんね
It must've been rough, eh?
大変だったね
Well then, Araragi.
それじゃあ　阿良々木くん
After you're a human again,
無事人間に戻ったら　もう軽率な行動を取らないよう気を付けてね
do be careful as to avoid any rash decisions.
After a person makes contact with an oddity,
怪異に一度行き逢った人間は
それからも引き摺られやすくなっちゃうから　気を付けて
it's easier for them to encounter one again.
Be careful.
Oi, what are you on about?
おい　何だよ
You make it sound like you're leaving for good.
もうここから出て行くみたいな言い方するなよ
I am leaving.
出て行くさ　仕事は済んだしね
My job's done.
I did make quite a mess of it, though.
失敗という形でだけど
But what's transpired has transpired,
what's done is done.
まあそれでも　済んだは済んだ　終わりは終わり
Ah.
ああそうだ　阿良々木くん
Before I forget, Araragi.
About that two million you owe me,
君の分の二百万円と委員長ちゃんの三百万円だけど
and the extra three million for Class Prez,
let's call it even.
あれはチャラってことでいいから
Don't glare at me like that,
そんな目をしなくとも裏はないよ
I'm not pulling a fast one.
This just sets my mind at ease.
これでも僕は気前がいいんだ
If a balance has been reached, I'm not gonna rock the boat.
バランスが取れてりゃうるさく言うつもりはない
そんなわけで　委員長ちゃんによろしくね
So on that note,
give my regards to Class Prez.
What's his deal?
何だよ
Kizumonogatari
III: The Ice-Blooded Chapter
本字幕由諸神製作 VCB-Studio壓制僅供試看使用不得將本片用於商業用途請與下載24小時之內刪除
如果您喜歡本作品請支援購買正版一切利用本片進行商業違法的行為與字幕組無關
日聽:小病　日校:驢驢　翻譯:沐沐、文承、顏歌　校對:キリサメ　時軸:小病　片源壓制:VCB-Studio
Yahoo!
I'm back!
戻った戻ったー
I'm back, baby!
Kiss-shot.
キスショット
About Oshino,
ちなみに忍野は昼間のうちにどっか行っちゃったみたいなんだけど
he left in the afternoon.
And what about it?
それがどうかしたかのう
I was just wondering.
いや　心臓の件怒らなくていいのかって
Shouldn't you be angry about your heart?
I care not. Not at all.
構わん構わん　許して遣わす
I shall overlook it.
I mean, who gives a shit!
っていうかどうでもいい
Uh, Kiss-shot.
キスショット　盛り上がっているところ悪いけれど
I'm sorry to rain on your parade,
but if it's okay with you,
もし良ければ　僕をさっさと人間に戻して欲しいんだけどな
I'd rather become human again as soon as possible.
Ah.
ああ　そうじゃったのう
'Tis understandable.
Fret not.
安心せい　ちゃんと戻してやるわい
I shall return thy humanity.
However, dear servant,
しかし従僕よ　その前に
before we get to that,
少し話をせんか
shall we have a chat?
Now then,
さて　何を話したものかのう
what shall we discuss?
You didn't have something you wanted to talk about?
話したいことがあるんじゃなかったのか
I suppose the way I phrased it was not quite right.
その言い方は正確ではなかったな
I did not have any one thing I wanted to converse about,
話したいことがあるのではなく　何でも良いから話したかっただけじゃ
but rather I merely wanted to hold a conversation; the subject matters not.
And is doing that something which is essential
それが僕を人間に戻すに当たって必要なことなのか
in turning me back into a human?
Is it vital.
必要じゃな　わしにとっては
To me, at least.
Well,
でもまあ　お前は五百年も生きてたんだ
you've lived for over 500 years.
I'm sure there's lots for you to talk about.
話の種は尽きないだろうが
There is nothing exciting, really.
特に何もなかったわい
My life has been one of fighting to the death with people such as those three.
あの三人のような連中とずっと殺し合いばかりしてきたからのう
At a fundamental level, it has been quite a tedious 500 years.
基本的には退屈な五百年じゃったよ
Now then, what shall we discuss
Now then, what shall w
then, what shall
Now then, what shall we discuss
then, shall we discuss
Now then, shall we discuss
I suppose...
そうじゃのう　話すべきことと言えば　やはりあの男のことしかないか
If I must speak of something,
the only matter of importance is the tale of that man.
I previously spoke of you
being the second kin I have produced.
汝がわしの作った二人目の眷属であることはもう話したな
So now
じゃからこれは　一人目の眷属の話じゃ
I shall speak of the first of my kindred.
Flashback
Yeah, you did mention that.
ああ　そう言えば言ってたっけ
That I was your second after 400 years.
四百年振り二人目とか
Was he kinda like me?
僕みたいなやつなのか
Why would you think that?
何故そう思う
Uh... Well... Err...
えっ　そ…それは
The only similary between you two
汝と被る部分は人種くらいじゃ
is thine ethnicity.
Damaged
GOOds
StOry
LOng
Since
Dama
ged
GOOds
StOry
Story
Art
Ueda Hajime
Nisio Isin
That man was a warrior.
そやつは戦士じゃったよ
One which I could entrust my rear flank to.
わしが背中を預けるに足る凄腕の戦士じゃった
A very skilled warrior.
I see.
But you said we shared ethnicity?
でも　人種は同じって言ったよな
Indeed. He was Japanese.
うん　日本人じゃ
During the period in which I was relishing my youth and travelling the globe,
若さにかまけて世界中を遊び歩いておった頃　この国で出会った男じゃよ
I met that man when I came to this country.
It was at that time that I learned Japanese.
日本語もその時に習った
But it seems the language has changed rather extensively.
まあ　随分と言葉は変わってしまったようじゃがのう
But if so,
でも　だったら　今回のこともそいつを呼んだら良かったのに
couldn't you have called upon him this time as well?
Impossible.
無理じゃよ
He has long since perished.
もう死んでおるからのう
And that, as well,
それも　かなり昔の話じゃ
happened a very long time ago.
Do you recall?
覚えておるか
I believe I mentioned that
わしが戦闘に当たって刀を使うことがあるという話をしたことがあったじゃろう
when I venture into battle I wield a certain sword.
And that weapon
その刀というのはそやつの形見じゃよ
is a memento of his.
The Magic Blade:
妖刀『心渡』
Heartspan.
It may be a nameless item from an eastern land,
無名の刀工の一品とのことじゃが　なかなかの業物らしいぞ
but apparently quite the myth surrounds it.
Do not move.
動くなよ
動くな　今汝を斬った
I just cut you.
Huh?
は…はあ？
Is there any pain?
痛みはあるか
N-No.
い…いや
That means my skills have not dulled.
となると　わしの腕も鈍ってはおらんようじゃな
You may move again.
もう動いて良いぞ　既に治癒しておる
It has healed.
What do you mean?
な…何だよそれ？
What healed?
治癒したって　僕の場合は服までは治癒しないだろう
I don't think it cut deep enough to require healing.
Where exactly did you slice?
どこを斬ったんだ
I split thee in two.
胴を横薙ぎにじゃ
Once again, I have cut a worthless object.
また　たまらぬものを斬ってしまった
Who are you calling worthless!?
たまらぬって
Worry not about thy clothes.
服のことも心配するな
The sharpness of Heartspan's bladed edge is authentic.
『心渡』の切れ味の鋭さは折り紙付きじゃ
So much so that if you but leave the threads alone they shall twine themselves back together.
切り口をしばらく放っておけば引っ付いてしまうほどにな
Of course,
無論　わしの腕があってのことじゃが
that is only if I am the one wielding the blade.
That man died
これを形見に　やつは死によった
and left this as a memento mori.
For an immortal vampire to have died,
不死身の吸血鬼が死んだってことは
that means,
つまり吸血鬼退治をされちまったってことか
he was exterminated by a hunter?
Nay.
違う
He was not the sort of man to be slain according to another's will.
やつは間違っても誰かに殺されるような男ではなかったよ
Then how?
じゃあ　なんで
Suicide.
自殺じゃ
Tedium will kill a man.
退屈は人を殺すというのじゃろう
Is what they say, is it not?
In most instances,
大抵の場合　吸血鬼は二百年も生きれば死にたくなってしまうようじゃな
a vampire will grow tired of existence after about 200 years.
So if there was one odd thing about that man,
その男に変わったところがあるとすれば
it was that he only lived a few years as a vampire
吸血鬼になってからわずか数年で自らの死を選んだというところじゃろうの
before he chose his own death.
Even though in that short time, nothing had really changed,
そんな短期間では大して何も変わらんというのに
he perished before my very eyes.
わしの目の前で死によった
I stared at him blazing under the sun,
太陽の下に身を投げて　これ見よがしに見せ付けながら
as I was forced to watch his death.
Ever since
以来　わしは眷属を作らんかった　汝に会うまでのう
I did not produce more kin.
Until I met you, that is.
Weren't you ever bored?
お前は退屈しなかったのか
I was bored witless
ずっと　暇じゃったよ
for the longest time.
However,
じゃが　汝には退屈させられんかったぞ　従僕よ
you did not allow me my malaise,
dear servant of mine.
You threw yourself headfirst into whatever needed to be done.
汝はやることなすこと無茶苦茶じゃった
You are probably the first human in history
吸血鬼に対し自分から首を突き出してくるような人間は
to willingly offer his neck to a vampire.
恐らく歴史上初めてじゃぞ
Not to mention you called me Kiss-short from the start.
わしのことをいきなりキスショット呼ばわりじゃしのう
さてと
Now then,
it is time.
そろそろ　汝を人間に戻すとするか
Shall we return thy humanity?
Yeah.
Now that I think about it,
そう言えば　一人目の眷属は人間に戻りたいとは言わなかったのか
did your first kin
ever say he wanted to be human again?
The me of that time
当時のわしには
could not possibly deliver him back unto humanity even if he so wished it.
どちらにしてもやつを人間に戻してやることはできんかったのでのう
This time I intend
今回はなるだけ　その教訓を活かしておるつもりじゃ
to make amends for what I could not do.
So,
で　準備はいいか
are you prepared?
Well,
いや…それが笑い過ぎたからか　ちょっと小腹が空いていてよ
I think I laughed a bit much.
I'm feeling a bit peckish.
Can we put something in our bellies first?
なんか腹に入れてからでもいいか
Very well.
まあ　確かにわしもいきなり完全体に戻って　空腹を感じてはおるのじゃが
It is true that since regaining my true form
I have been tinged with hunger.
Can you procure some of those mobile snacks?
携帯食でも持ってくる気か
"Mobile snacks"?
携帯食って
Well,
まあ　吸血鬼としても最後の夜だし　ちっとは名残惜しみたいってところさ
this is my last night as a vampire.
Might as well go out with a bang.
Is there anything in particular you want to eat?
お前　なんか食べたいものでもあるか
I have no real preference.
わしに好き嫌いはないの
Anything shall suffice.
まあ良い　いいようにせよ　我が従僕よ
Make fruitful of the night, dear servant of mine.
If only for a short while, you have been a fine servant.
少しでも長い間わしの従僕でいたいという汝の心意気は買ってやろう
Sate your spirits.
I shall be preparing on the second floor.
わしは二階で準備をしておる
Got it.
オッケー
So I guess
やっぱ　どっか行っちゃうんだろうな
she really is going away somewhere.
Can't do anything about it.
まあ　仕方ないことか
Farewell
If there is a meeting,
出会いもあれば別れもあるだろう
there will surely be a farewell.
Even if to Kiss-shot
キスショットにとっては悪い思い出ばかりの二週間だったとしても
these two weeks have been full of nothing but bad memories,
looking back on it now,
今になって思えば　僕にとってはそんな悪くない春休みだったのかもしれない
to me,
it wasn't that bad a spring break.
It wasn't that bad at all.
そんな悪くなかったのかもしれない
Following our little chat on the roof,
屋根の上での打ち上げに続いて　送別会も開いてしまおう
we'll have ourselves a farewell party.
And then, finally, I'll properly say some words of parting
そして　ちゃんと別れの言葉をキスショットに告げよう
to Kiss-shot, in earnest.
I'm back!
ただいまー
Oh, dear servant.
おぉ　従僕　意外と早かったのう
That was quicker than expected.
However, I believe I made myself clear before:
しかし言っておるじゃろう
It is only proper manners to leave a lady to herself when she eats.
レディーの食事中は席を外すのがマナーじゃぞ
Whilst I was awaiting thy return,
汝を待っていたら　こいつがやってきたものでのう
this one decided to pay us a visit.
And of course I could penetrate
さすがの結界もフルパワーのわしの力は隠し切れなかったようじゃな
the barrier and discover him easily with my full power.
And what is this?
なんじゃ　汝　眼鏡で三つ編みのあの携帯食持って来んかったのか
Did you not bring along that mobile snack
with the glasses and the plait?
April 7th
I believed men of such raw faith to be rather unappetising.
聖職者はまずいと相場が決まっておるのじゃが
However!
しかしなかなかの美味であったわ
This is quite the delicacy!
I thought myself to not have preferences,
好き嫌いはないつもりじゃったが
but whoever said that "hunger is the ultimate spice"
しかし空腹は最高のソースとはよく言ったものじゃのう
really knew what they were talking about!
No...
いや…
You can't eat...
人間を食べちゃ…駄目だろう
a human being.
But,
しかし従僕よ　食べなければ死んでしまうぞ
dear servant,
if I do not eat, I shall perish.
For her entire existence
ずっと　食べてきたのだろう
she has eaten.
She has continually sated her hunger.
食べ続けてきたのだろう
Her first kin.
一人目の眷属　そして二人目
And the second.
During her 500 years,
五百年生きて　血を吸った相手がその二人だけのはずもない
she's only stopped at just drinking blood
for her two kindred.
Every other human being
それ以外の人間は　すべてああいうふうに
has been, in that violent manner,
torn to shreds,
ばらばらにして　肉も骨も残さずに食べてきたのだ
leaving neither meat nor bone,
and consumed as food.
For that is how she acquires nutrients
それが眷属を作らない場合の彼女の栄養補給
when she is not producing kin.
From now own, whenever Kiss-shot eats a human,
今後キスショットが人間を食べれば…食事を取れば…
whenever she sates her appetite,
it will undoubtedly be
それはすべて僕の責任だ
due to my actions.
If Hanekawa is eaten,
羽川が食われても
if my sisters are eaten,
妹たちが食われても
if my parents are eaten,
両親が食われても
that would be entirely
それはすべて　僕のせいだ
my fault.
It's my fault becaused I saved her.
僕が彼女を助けたせいだ
My fault.
僕のせいで
My fault!
I can't...
もう　嫌だ…
Take it anymore.
I can't stand the thought of it.
嫌なのに…
It makes me sick.
But I, too,
僕だって　吸血鬼だ
am a vampire.
Ah, that reminds me.
ああそうそう
have you had any
最近　お腹空かない？
hunger pangs recently?
What do I do about this?
どうするんだよこれ　死ぬしかないじゃん
I have to die.
There's no other option.
死ぬしかない
Yes, that's right.
ああ　そうだ
But,
でも　羽川には言いたかったよな
I really want to speak to Hanekawa.
I deleted both her mobile number
携帯番号もメルアドも　僕が自ら消去した
and her email of my own accord.
In front of her very eyes.
彼女の目の前で
In order to inflict lasting pain on her.
彼女を傷付けるために消去した
I purged everything.
I thought I told her
だから　勝手に人の携帯弄んなっつーの
not to just mess
with my phone.
Your girl has been delivered.
女の子の届け物です
What do I say about this?
何だかなー
I've been tricked into coming to the gymnasium storage room and now we're trapped!
うまいこと体育倉庫に閉じ込められちゃったみたい
If Araragi decides to play an indecent trick on me,
阿良々木くんに嫌らしい悪戯とかされたらどうしよう
whatever will I do?
Flashlight:
懐中電灯　オン
on!
Ah!
We're sitting like this because you want to peek at my panties.
正面座ってパンツ見ようとしてる
You are under a gross misunderstanding as to the kind of man I am.
お前は僕という男を誤解している
For example, if before my very eyes,
僕はたとえ目の前に裸の女の子がいたとしても
a stark naked woman was standing there,
and she told me not to look at her,
その子が見ないでと言ったら見ないことができる男だ
I would be able to resist looking.
それは普通
That's true for most people.
No, I mean, Hanekawa,
いや　羽川　僕がどれほどのジェントルメンなのかお前は知らないだけなんだよ
you just don't understand the extent
to which I am a gentlemen.
"Gentlemen" is a plural.
ジェントルメンは複数形
But, well,
まあ　それが本当なんだったら　私としては楽しみだよね
if you are speaking the truth,
I'm looking forward to seeing it.
Looking forward...
楽しみって何が
to what?
Well, when the new school term starts,
新学期になったら
I'll be able to see lots and lots
私は阿良々木くんのジェントルなところをいっぱい見られるってことでしょう
of your gentle side, won't I?
So that's why...
だから　死んじゃ駄目だよ
You can't...
Die...
You're not allowed
死んじゃ駄目
to die.
If you're thinking about things like that,
そんなふうに考えるのは　心が逃げてる証拠だよ
it just proves that you're running away from your feelings.
You...
お前は…すげーよ
You're amazing.
You're...
お前はすごい
incredible.
When I'm here with you
お前を前にしていると　自分がひどくつまらない人間のように思えてくるよ
I finally realise what an insignificant human I am.
If I hadn't met you,
多分お前に会ってなかったら　僕はもっと早く死んでたと思う
I would have probably died a lot earlier.
That's why I'm trying to say...
いやだから　死んじゃ駄目だって言ってるじゃない
You just can't go and die!
Listen to what
私の話　聞いてよ
I have to say.
Everything's...
全部　僕のせいなんだよ
my fault.
My reckless actions
僕の軽はずみな行動がこんな結果を生んじまった
have led to this miserable result.
You know, I...
僕はさ　あの時　キスショットに血をやった時
when I yielded my blood to Kiss-shot,
I never would have ever fathomed
こんなことになるなんてまるで思っていなかった
that any of this would happen.
It's my fault that...
僕のせいで　人が死んだ
a person died.
It isn't your fault, Araragi.
阿良々木くんのせいじゃないよ
And besides,
それに　ハートアンダーブレードさんにとっては
from Heart-Under-Blade's point of view,
that would've been a very mundane occurance.
それは　とても当たり前のことなんだろうね
It's the same to her as
私たちが　牛さんや豚さんを食べるのと同じことなんだよね
eating cows and pigs
is to us, right?
ああ　だからキスショットは悪くない　悪いのは僕だ
Yeah.
So Kiss-shot isn't at fault.
The one at fault here is me.
It's all my fault.
僕が悪い　他には誰も悪くない
No one else did anything wrong.
Besides,
それに　まさか思わなかったよ
I never
thought, even once, that
Dramaturgy,
ドラマツルギー　エピソード　ギロチンカッター
Episode,
and Guillotine-Cutter—
that those three were on the side of human justice.
あの三人が人間側の正義だったなんて
I became an enemy of humanity.
僕は人間の敵になってしまった
So is that why
だから　人間に戻るのは諦めるの？
you've given up on
becoming human again?
Have you forsaken your humanity?
阿良々木くんは人間を諦めたの？
Didn't you say that you really...
人間に戻りたいって　現実に戻りたいって　そう言ってたじゃない
wanted to become human...
to come back to reality!?
Now that there's a victim,
犠牲者が出てしまったんだ
granting my own desires
今更僕だけが望みを叶えるなんて　あまりにも虫が良過ぎるよ
would be far too selfish of me.
If you want to talk about selfishness,
虫がいいって言うなら　今の阿良々木くんの方が虫が良くない？
aren't you being far more selfish
acting the way you are now?
I mean,
だって　自分が仕出かしたことを全部投げ出して逃げようとしている
you want to throw everything you've done into the wind
and just run away from it all!
You're just running away,
心も逃げてるし　体も逃げてる
in body and soul!
You're wrong.
違うよ
I don't want to run away.
逃げたいんじゃなくて　責任を取りたいんだよ
I want to take responsibility.
Extinguishing this immortal body with my own hands
この不死身の命を自ら絶つのが僕にとってのせめてもの罪滅ぼしだ
is the least I can do to atone for my sins.
If you try to erase sin with sin,
罪に罪を重ねるだけだよ
you'll only add to your sins.
Suicide is, after all,
自殺は罪だよ
a sin.
Hanekawa...
羽川…
Hanekawa.
羽川
Hm?
今の僕は人間じゃない　吸血鬼だ
As I am now, I'm not a human being.
I'm a vampire.
だから…
So...
I'm not like you.
僕はお前と違って弱い人間だから
I'm a weak person.
今死なないと　きっとずるずるイっちまう
So if I don't die now, I'm sure, given time,
いずれ食欲に勝てなくなる
I'll give into the temptation to feed.
羽川　お前のことも　いずれ僕には食べ物にしか見えなくなる
Hanekawa...
Sooner or later I'll only be able to view you as something to be eaten.
だったら　食べなよ
So then eat me.
な…何言ってんだ　お前
Wha—
What are you saying?
相手のために死ねないのなら　私はその人のことを友達とは呼ばない
If I can't die for a person,
then I wouldn't call that person my friend.
だから言ったでしょう？
I told you that you'd be disillusioned by how I really am.
本当の私を知ったら幻滅するって
お…お前一体　何なんだよ
What in the world....
are you?
うん？　阿良々木くんの友達のつもりだけど
Hmm?
I believe that I'm your friend.
それだけで普通　ここまで関わってくるか
No ordinary person...
Would go that far for a friend.
前にも言ったけど
I asked you this before,
会ったばかりの僕のために　どうしてそこまでできるんだよ
but how are you able to go so far for someone you just recently met?
誰にでもそんなことしたなら　体がいくつあっても足りないだろう
If you're that devoted to just anyone, you wouldn't have nearly enough lives to give.
誰にでもなんてしないけど
But you're not just anyone.
阿良々木くんだから　してるんだよ
I can do this because it's you, Araragi.
大体　阿良々木くん一人を助けるためだったら
Besides, if it's just to save one little Araragi,
体なんて一つあったら十分だよ
putting a single body on the line is more than enough!
だから　死んじゃ駄目
So that's why...
you can't die.
死なないで
Don't die.
完全復活した
There's no one who can stop
キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードを
Kiss-shot Acerola-Orion Heart-Under-Blade,
when she's at her full strength.
止められるものはいない
僕の責任で復活したあいつは臆面もなく人を食い続けるだろう
I'm responsible for her recovery,
and she'll continuing eating people without batting an eyelash.
It was impossible for Gullotine-Cutter,
ギロチンカッターには無理だった
so Dramaturgy or Episode wouldn't put up any sort of fight.
ドラマツルギーやエピソードでも　絶対に相手にならないだろう
強いて可能性をあげるとするなら忍野だが
The only one with a slight chance, Oshino,
あいつは絶対に　バランスを取る以上のことをしてくれない
will never do anything that upsets the balance.
あいつにとってキスショットの件はもう終わっていることなんだ
To him,
everything relating to Kiss-shot has already been settled.
もう誰にもあの吸血鬼を止められないんだよ
There's no one who can put a stop to that vampire.
阿良々木くんにも？
Even you?
阿良々木くんには　止められるんじゃないの？
Wouldn't you be able to stop her?
どころか　もう　阿良々木くんにしか止められないんじゃないの？
In fact,
you're the only left who can stop her.
唯一の眷属である阿良々木くんは
Aren't you, her only kin,
逆に言えば唯一　彼女を止められる存在なんじゃないの？
conversely, the only one who can put a stop to her?
On your marks...
位置に着いて
Get set...
よーい
僕が…
I will... Go up against Kiss-shot.
僕が…キスショットを退治する
表情が変わったね
Your expression's changed.
大丈夫だ
It'll be fine.
僕はちゃんとあいつを退治する
I will definitely exterminate her.
じゃあ　私も勿論協力する
Well then, I'll have to help you out, of course.
私にできることがあるなら　遠慮しないで言って
If there's anything I can do, don't hesitate to ask.
まあそうは言っても
I say that but, I can't think of any lewder acts you could ask of me more than what I've already done.
あれ以上エッチなサービスなんて私には思い付かないけどね
羽川
Hanekawa.
What is it?
何？
胸を触らせてはもらえないだろうか
Would you allow me to touch your breasts?
胸を…
Your bre—
いや　聞こえたし
I heard you.
Um... And why exactly is that necessary?
えーと…それはどうして必要なことなのかな
It is extremely necessary.
どうしても必要なことだ
You haven't seen it yet.
お前は見ていないんだったな
Kiss-shot Acerola-Orion Heart-Under-Blade's fully powered
完全体のキスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードが
どんな姿なのか
form, that is.
Well, no.
まあ…でも12歳と17歳の姿を見ているから
But I've seen her 12 and 17 year old forms so
27歳の姿っていうのも想像付かなくもないけれど…
I can kind of imagine what her 27 year old form is like.
恐らく想像以上だ
It is most likely beyond that.
想像以上の胸をやつは持っている
She has a bust beyond your wildest imagination.
胸を…
Bust?
I am deathly afraid that I'll be distracted by her
voluptuous bosom and be defeated because of it.
あの胸に気を取られているうちに負けてしまうことが僕の不安だ
多分あの胸は戦闘中にすごく揺れる
Those breasts of hers will probably be swaying madly during the fight.
だからその対策として女子の胸に対する修行を積みたい
So in order to counteract that, I need to build up a tolerance to a woman's breasts.
お…思いの外　くだらない理由だよ
That's a far more trivial reason than I was expecting.
い…一応理屈は通ってないか
Doesn't the flow of logic make a bit of sense?
いいでしょう
Very well!
えっ　いいの
What? Really?!
ちょっと…待って
Just...
wait a bit.
阿良々木くん
Araragi.
え？　あ　何？
Yes?
揉むからにはきちんと揉みなさい
If you're going to fondle them, do it properly.
き…きちんと？
Properly?
60秒以上は揉むべきだと思う
You should fondle them for at least sixty seconds.
ろ…60
Sixty seconds!?
手加減無用
Do not hold back!
お…おぉ
あ…あのさ　羽川
You know what, Hanekawa...
後ろを向いてもらっていいかな
Could I get you to face the other way?
Looking you in the eyes during...
顔を見ながらというのは厳しいんだけど
Would be a bit rough.
りょ…両手を上に上げて
Raise your arms in the air.
ラジオ体操ですか
What is this, radio calisthenics?
あ…後で怒ったりしない？
You won't be mad later?
It's okay. I won't get mad.
大丈夫　怒りません
絶対？
You mean it?
絶対です
I mean it.
Well then, you know...
じゃあ　その…なんだろう
万が一裁判になった時のために
In the unlikely event that this goes to court...
"Araragi, would you be so kind as to fondle my bra-less breasts".
「阿良々木くん　どうか私のノーブラおっぱいをモミモミしてください　お願いします」
"I beg of you". Could you say that for me?
と言っておいてくれるかな
あ…阿良々木くん
A-Araragi!
ど…どうか　私のノーブラおっぱいをモミモミしてください
Would you be so kind as to fondle my bra-less breasts...
お願い…お願いします
I... I beg of you.
いや　そんな小さな声で言われても困るよ
No. Saying it in such a soft voice won't do at all.
それじゃあまるで嫌がる羽川に僕が無理やり言わせてるみたいじゃないか
It's almost as if I'm forcing you
to say it against your will.
もっと大きな声で　自分のどこをどうして欲しいのか
You have to speak up and tell me exactly where and what you want.
羽川自身の意思でちゃんと言ってくれないと
You have to say it of your own volition.
A-Araragi!
阿良々木くん　ど…どうか私のノーブラおっぱいをモミモミしてください
Please be so kind as to fondle my bra-less breasts!
I beg of you!
お願いします
「阿良々木くんにおっぱいを揉んでもらえるなんてとても光栄です」
"It would be the greatest honour to have my breasts fondled by you, Araragi."
It would be...
阿良々木くんに…おっぱいを揉んでもらえるなんて　と…とても光栄です
the greatest honour...
to have my breasts fondled by you, Araragi.
Sadistic
えっと…
Let's see...
"I nurtured these lascivious breasts for the sole purpose of getting them fondled by you, Araragi."
「阿良々木くんに揉んでもらうためだけに頑張ってこんな嫌らしいおっぱいに育てました」
阿良々木くんに揉んで…揉んでもらうためだけに
I nurtured these lascivious breasts...
For the sole purpose of getting them fondled by you, Araragi.
頑張って　こんな嫌らしいおっぱいに育てました
えー　そんなふうには見えなかったけど
Is that so? It sure doesn't look that way.
羽川って結構エッチなんだな
You're quite raunchy, aren't you?
はい　私はとてもエッチです　ごめんなさい
Yes, I'm very perverted.
I'm sorry!
別に謝る必要はないさ
There's no need to apologise, really.
No matter how lewd you are, Hanekawa,
羽川がたとえどんなにエッチでも　誰かが迷惑するわけじゃないんだから
it's not as if you're causing anyone any problems.
そ…そうですね
That's true...
And so?
それで　エッチで真面目な委員長さんのおっぱいは
How exactly are the breasts of our diligent, yet indecent, class president lewd?
具体的にはどういうふうに嫌らしいんだ
お…大きさと柔らかさがこれ以上ない嫌らしさだと…自負しています
Their size and softness...
There exists no other pair of breasts as conceitedly lewd as these!
Climax
ああ　そうか　そうだったのか
So that's it. I understand now.
僕の人生はこの日のためにあったんだ
My entire life was for the purpose of this moment.
今日という日を体験するためだけに
The person known as Araragi Koyomi was born into this world
阿良々木暦という人間はこの世に生まれてきたんだ
just to experience this day!
っていうか　友達の乳を揉むとか普通に無理ですから
What was I doing? I can't just fondle my friend's breasts!
ないって　やっぱこれはないって
This isn't right! We can't do this!
チキン
Chicken.
Chicken. Chicken. Chicken. Chicken. Chicken. Chicken. Chicken.
チキン　チキン　チキンチキンチキンチキンチキン
I'm a chicken! I'm a disappointment! I'm sorry!
チキンです　ヘタレです　すいません
羽川さんの優しさに甘えてしまいました…が
I was swayed by your unwavering kindess!
However! My eyes have been opened by your actions!
その身を張った行為のおかげで目が覚めました
それで済むと思う？
Do you think you'll get off that easily?
Do you understand how much resolve it took
私が一体どれくらいの覚悟を決めて　こんなふうにここに座ってるんだと思う？
to be sitting here as I am now?
い…いえ　僕如き存在にはまるで見当も付きませんが…
N-no.
A worthless person such as myself could not even begin to grasp it.
その…ち…ちなみにどれくらいの覚悟だったのか
B-but how resolved were you, by the way?
聞かせていただけますでしょうか
Would you be so kind as to let me ask that?
正直　胸を揉まれるくらいじゃ済まないんだろうなって思ってた
To be frank, I was ready for it to go past mere breast fondling.
ああそっか　そうなんだ
I thought "Ahh, this is how it's gonna go."
私の初めてって学校の体育倉庫のマットの上になるんだなって
"My first time is gonna be on top of a mat in the gymnasium storage room."
覚悟決めるの早過ぎませんか
Were you perhaps jumping the gun just a little?
まあありかなって
Well, I thought it could happen.
ありなんだ
IT COULD'VE!?
Frustration
それなのに　散々焦らして辱めたあげく　指一本触れさえもせず
And yet, you put me through
a very embarassing situation
and didn't even lay a finger on me!
阿良々木くん…そんなに私　魅力ないかな
Araragi, am I really that unattractive?
か…代わりに肩を揉むというのではどうでしょうか
How does a shoulder massage sound instead?
肩？
Shoulder?
はい　肩です
Yes, your shoulders.
羽川さんの肩が揉みたいです
I want to massage your shoulders.
以上です　ありがとうございました
That concludes my service. Thank you very much.
もういいの？
Are you done?
Yes. See what happens next on the web.
は…はい　続きはウェブで
As if I'll get fondled on the web!
ウェブで揉まれてたまりますか
Then how about, we pick this up in the new semester?
じゃ…じゃあ続きは新学期…とか
うん　そうだね
You're right.
女の子にここまでさせた以上
If you forced a girl through all this, there's no way that you're planning on losing now, right?
まさか負けるってことはないよね
Yo.
そっちから来てくれるとは思わなかったぜ
I didn't think you'd be coming to me.
一度だけじゃ
I shall say this once.
従僕よ　太陽の出ている間に汝の気持ちは理解した
Servant of mine, whilst the sun was shining between us, I managed to grasp the intent behind your feelings.
どうしてあれほど怒ったのか　その理由も理解した
I understand why you grew so irate.
I understand the reason.
元人間の汝に対し　あまりに配慮が足りなかったとも思う
I think that I did not give due consideration to your position as a former human.
So just this once,
じゃから一度だけ　頭を下げてやる
I will ask this of you:
わしの下に帰れ
return to my side.
わしと共に生きよ
Live alongside me.
わしは汝に命を助けられた
My life was saved by you.
汝は変なやつじゃが　じゃからこそ汝となら生きても良いとわしは思っておる
You are an eccentric fellow, but that is exactly why I feel I can live alongside you.
わしと共に永劫の時を生きる気はないか
Do you have no wish to exist with me for all of eternity?
断る
I do not.
お前は人を食った　僕にとってはそれだけで十分だ
You ate someone.
That's reason enough for me.
それが分かっていたら　汝はわしを助けなかったのか
If that is your understanding,
then why did you save me?
見殺しにしておったというのか
Why did you not leave me to die?
I didn't understand a single damn thing.
僕は何も分かっちゃいなかったんだ
いや　違うな
No, that's not right.
やっぱり最初から分かっちゃいたんだ
I actually did understand from the start.
ただ　目を逸らしていただけなんだ
But I averted my eyes to that fact.
お前のために死のうと　僕は思ったんだからな
Because I thought I wanted to die for your sake.
それはつまり　お前が人を食うことを許容したってことだ
So what I'm saying,
is that I pardoned your consumption of people.
でも　そのせいで人が死ぬところまで僕は想像していなかった
But I never even imagined that people would die because of it.
My feelings may have been beautiful in their concept,
僕の行為は美しくはあっても正しくはなかった
but they were not righteous.
汝はそう言うと思っておった
I thought you would say as such.
汝がそう言うのを聞きたかった
I wanted to hear you say that.
これでわしから迷いは消えた
Now I can extinguish all hesitation.
従僕よ　わしもな　最初からなんとなく分かっておったよ
Dear servant,
I had an inclination from the very beginning.
汝はそういうやつじゃろうと思っておった
I thought that you were perhaps that sort of person.
Hypocrisy
汝が優しいのはわしが弱っておる間だけじゃろうとな
Your kindness was
only directed towards me whilst I was weak.
そう分かっておった
That's right. I understood.
H
Y
P
O
C
R
I
T
E
!
H
Y
P
O
C
R
I
T
E
!
Now that I have regained my full power,
完全なる存在になったわしには　汝は興味を持たんとそう思っておったのじゃ
I think that
you have no interest in me any longer.
Hypocrisy
汝はわしだから助けたのではない
You did not save me because I was me.
You would have saved anyone, had they shown weakness.
弱っていれば　誰でも助けたのじゃ
Hypocrisy
H
Y
P
O
C
R
I
T
E
!
H
Y
P
O
C
R
I
T
E
!
W
a
h
W
a
h
ほれ　もっと近こう寄れ　従僕よ
Come now. Draw closer, servant.
汝が直接にわしを殺せば　汝は大好きな人間に戻れるのじゃぞ
If you kill me with your own hands,
you can reclaim your beloved humanity.
キスショット　僕もお前に　最後に聞きたいことがある
Kiss-shot,
there's something
I would like to ask you.
ほぉ　いいじゃろう
Really?
Go ahead.
冥土の土産じゃ　何でも答えてやる　聞いてみよ
As a parting gift for the underworld,
I shall answer anything you ask.
Ask away.
お前にとって人間って何だ
To you,
what is a human?
食料
A meal.
I wanted to hear you say that.
僕もお前がそう言うのを聞きたかった
死んでくれ　我が主人
Please die, my master!
Thou art to perish, servant of mine!
死ぬが良い　我が従僕
いいのう　これが吸血鬼同士の殺し合いの醍醐味じゃ
Excellent! This is the very essence of a fight to the death between vampiric bretheren!
もっと　もっとじゃ　従僕
More! Do it more, servant!
ところで　一ついいことを教えてやろうか　従僕よ
By the way, I will tell you something nice, servant.
It is unfortunate that these will be my parting words to you.
これでお別れとなる汝が知っても仕方のないことじゃがのう
What?
The truth is, I too was once human.
わしも実は元人間なんじゃよ
元人間
A former human.
That is to say, the very same as you and Dramaturgy.
つまりはドラマツルギーや汝と同じじゃのう
ああ？　純正じゃなかったのか
Weren't you a pure blood?
人間だった頃のことはほとんど忘れてしもうたがのう
I have forgotten most of my time as a human, however,
それなりにいい家柄じゃったようじゃぞ
apparently I was from quite a good pedigree.
まあ年齢が三百を越えた吸血鬼には
Well, to a vampire of over 300 years,
もう純正も眷属もあったものではないがのう
purity and kindred no longer hold much meaning.
それがどうした
And so what of it!?
いや　久しく忘れておったというだけじゃ
Nothing. I had just forgotten, is all.
昨夜汝と言い合って　思い出したわ
I remembered something when I was with you last night.
そう言えばわしも　最初は人を食うことに躊躇いを覚えておったとな
I think you should know.
When I first ate human flesh, I recall that I hesitated.
だったら…
If that's the case—
汝とて
Even for you,
一人でも人を食えば　そのような罪悪感は消えてなくなるのじゃぞ
the sense of guilt would disappear for each human you consumed.
キスショット　僕は人間なんだよ
Kiss-shot,
I am a human being.
そうか　わしは吸血鬼じゃ
Is that so? I am a vampire.
いよいよ　最後　日本選手団の入場であります
It's finally time for the final Japanese athletes to take their places.
栄光への道を求めて　苦しい試練に耐え抜き
They have withstood many tribulations on their path to glory.
今　堂々と胸を張って歩く日本の若者
And now, the youth of Japan step up, full of pride.
思えば　昭和15年五輪東京誘致が決まりましたが
Looking back, Tokyo was to have held the 1940 Olympics Games.
戦いの日にその夢は流され…
But the rising conflict shattered many dreams.
ちょっと待って
Hold it right there!
5年前　東京大会が正式に決まり
Five years prior, the atheletes for the competition were decided in Tokyo.
それから5年　日本人の一人一人のすべての努力は
And then over the next five years, all their efforts have lead up to this moment...
阿良々木くん　何かおかしい
Araragi, something isn't right!
羽川　いいから隠れてろ
Hanekawa, hurry up and go hide!
今日この日のために払われた感じがいたします
ち…違うの　さっきからすごく変なの
No, you don't get it. Something's been off for a while!
アジアで　初めて開かれた世紀の祭典
私たち多分まだ何かとても大事なことを見落としている…
平和と人間愛と勇気の第18回オリンピック東京大会
I think we've been overlooking something very important this entire time.
喧しいわ
You're a nuisance!
よ…余計なことを言うな　携帯食が
Don't you dare say anything unnecessary, you mobile snack.
ハートアンダーブレードさん　あなた　ひょっとして…
Heart-Under-Blade,
could it be that you—
人間風情が出しゃばるな
You damnable human!
Don't butt in!
What is the matter, dear servant?
どうした　従僕
まだわしの血は半分ほど残っておるようじゃぞ
I still have about half of my blood left.
Having had so much of my blood drained, I can no longer move.
ここまで血を抜かれてしまえば今はもう動けんが
しかし早くせねば　わしはすぐに復活すると思うが
However, if you do not put an end to me soon, I shall soon rejuvenate.
お前…どうやって僕を人間に戻すつもりだったんだ
How exactly were you planning on making me human again?
そんなことが今の汝に関係あるのか
Does such a thing really matter to you as you are now?
ハートアンダーブレードさん
Heart-Under-Blade,
あなた…最初から　阿良々木くんに殺されるつもりだったんですか
did you intend for Araragi to kill you from the very start?
In order to for him to become human again?
阿良々木くんを人間に戻すために
Do not jest, mobile snack.
戯けたことを言うなよ　携帯食　何の根拠があって…
What are you basing that on?
じゃあ　どうやって阿良々木くんを人間に戻すつもりだったのか
Then how exactly were you planning on making him human again?
それを教えてください
Please tell us that.
知れたことよ
You already know.
わしにはそもそもこの従僕を人間に戻す気がなかったというだけのことじゃ
I had no intention of returning this servant of mine to humanity at all.
わしの手足を集めさせるために　嘘を付いておったというだけのことよ
I merely fed him falsehoods so that he would retrieve my extremities.
違います
You're lying.
欠けたパーツを集めさせたのは
The reason you got him to reclaim all your parts was because, if you were not complete,
たとえ不完全な状態で阿良々木くんに殺されたとしても
それじゃあ阿良々木くんは人間には戻れないからでしょう
his killing of you wouldn't return his humanity.
There was no meaning behind his killing of you unless you were fully complete.
完全体に戻ってから殺されないと意味がないから
あなたは…死ぬつもりなんです
You were
planning on dying.
And what exactly do you hope to gain by saying all this?
汝　そんなことを言ってどうするつもりじゃ
そんなことを言って　この従僕にわしを殺すことができると思うのか
Do you really believe my servant can kill me now that he has heard all of that?
な…なんで
W-Why...
お前がどうして　そんなことを…
Why would you do any of that...
わしはのう　死に場所を探しておったのじゃ
I was already looking for a place to die.
死んでもいいと思っておった　そのはずじゃった
I thought it would be nice to die.
Or at least I did.
しかし　最後に死ぬのが怖くなった
However, at the last moment, I became afraid of death.
五百年生きた自分が消えることが怖くなった
After 500 years of existence, I was terrified of suddenly disappearing.
自分がいなくなってしまうことが怖くて怖くてどうしようもなくなった
The thought of no longer existing scared me, frightened me to no end.
わしは生まれて初めて他人に助けられた
It was the first time in my life that a stranger lent me aid.
人間にも吸血鬼にも　助けられたことなどなかったよ
From neither human nor vampire
had I ever received assistance.
そんな汝の血を吸っているうちにわしは何をしておるのかと思った
And so, as I was extracting your kind blood, I began to question my actions.
じゃから　わしは汝のために死のうと
So please,
allow me to die for your sake.
I could not die for his sake.
わしはやつのために死ねんかった　死んでやることができんかった
I could not bring myself to die for him.
やつを人間に戻してやることができんかった
I could not bequeath his humanity unto him.
じゃから…
So please...
なんじゃ　汝　泣いておるのか
What is this? Art thou crying?
泣き虫じゃのう　我が従僕は情けない
You sure are a crybaby.
How pathetic for a servant of mine.
ち…違う　これは涙じゃない
No, these aren't tears.
これは…
This is... this is just...
これは…血だ
Blood. My blood is just flowing.
血が流れてるんだ
お前にだって　血は流れてるだろう
Blood flows within you as well, doesn't it?
全く　余計な真似をしてくれたな　携帯食
Good grief. You really took some unwarranted action, mobile snack.
I was planning on letting my guard down at an inauspicious juncture and forfeiting my life...
適当なところで隙を見せて殺されてやるつもりじゃったのに
じゃが　まあ良いわ
But this is fine.
For you have no other option other than to kill me, after all.
所詮汝には　わしを殺す以外の選択肢は残ってはおらんのじゃからな
わしを殺さねば　わしは明日から　一日千人の人間を食おう
For if you cannot kill me, every day from tomorrow henceforth I shall feast on 1000 humans.
こう言えば　汝はわしを殺すしかなくなるじゃろう
And, knowing that, now your only choice is to kill me.
To prove that was no idle threat,
if I seize that mobile snack at the outset,
脅しでない証拠に
手始めにそこの携帯食を横取りしてやれば踏ん切りも付くか
you shall witness my determination.
助けた命は自分で摘むが良い
You should be accountable for those you save.
それが責任とかいうやつなのじゃろう
That is what they call a "sense of responsibility", is it not?
キスショット
Kiss-shot!
その名でわしを呼ぶものも汝で二人目じゃ
You are the second to call me by that name.
そして最後の一人となる
But you shall be the last.
さあ　わしを殺すが良い　従僕
Now, you are to kill me,
dear servant.
さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ　さあ
Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. DO IT!
DO IT
畜生
Damn it all!
Oshino! Oshino Meme!
忍野
忍野メメ
I know you're watching this from somewhere!
どうせどっかで見ているんだろう
So stop dicking around and show yourself!
勿体付けてねーでさっさと出てきやがれ
I finally understand everything you were trying to tell me!
お前の言っていたことは全部分かった
I'm not looking for any explanations anymore, so get out here already!
もう何の説明も求めない
だから出て来い　自分が何をしたかも分かった
I know exactly what position I'm in!
So show yourself, Oshino Meme!
だから出て来い　忍野メメ
You don't have to yell that loudly; I can hear you.
そんな怒鳴らなくても聞こえるよ
What a coincidence, meeting you in a place like this, Araragi!
阿良々木くん　こんなところで会うなんて空前だね
Oshino!
忍野
This is the feistiest I've ever seen somebody.
全く以て阿良々木くんは元気いいなぁ
Did something good happen?
何かいいことでもあったのかい
I have a job for you.
仕事の依頼だ　何とかしてくれ
Do something about this.
Do something? That's rather vague.
何とかって　曖昧だね
I'll pay you.
金は払う
It's not an issue of finances.
金の問題じゃない
Then what is the problem?
じゃあ何の問題だ
It's your own personal problem.
自分の問題だろ
Don't try and force it.
押し付けるなよ
Heya, Class Prez.
やぁ　委員長ちゃん
This is our first meeting, right?
初めまして…だね
It's nice to meet you. I'm Hanekawa.
初めまして　羽川です
Don't get in the way, brat.
小僧　邪魔をするなよ　そういう約束じゃろう
Wasn't that the deal?
I have no recollection of making a deal with you,
君と約束をした覚えはないよ　ハートアンダーブレード
Heart-Under-Blade.
I merely wished to accumulate all the information I could acquire.
僕はただいいように状況を整えたかっただけだ
In order to restore Araragi's humanity,
君が阿良々木くんを人間に戻すために自らの死を選ぶというのなら
your choice of self-sacrifice
suited my needs perfectly, is all.
それが僕にとっては都合が良かったというだけさ
So, what're you gonna do?
で　どうする？
You've got a job request for a specialist like me, don't you?
専門家たる僕への仕事の依頼だよね
For the fee, let's see...
料金は…そうだな　チャラにしてあげた五百万円を引き継ぐってことにしよう
let's set it at the five million we called even before.
Now, what's the request?
で　君の望みは？
I want you to tell me a way for everyone to be satisfied.
みんなが幸せになる方法を教えて欲しい
A way I can put an end to this without anyone being dissatisfied.
誰も不幸にならずに済む　そんな方法を…
There's no way that's possible.
あるわけないじゃん　そんなの
Are you an idiot?
馬鹿じゃないの
However, there is a way for everyone to be dissatisfied.
ただし　みんなが不幸になる方法ならある
That is to say, there may be a method for divvying up
つまり　今回のことによって生じる不幸を分散して背負うって話さ
the unhappiness between multiple parties.
No one single person's wishes would be fulfilled, but if you're fine with that I'll tell you the way.
誰の望みも叶わないけれど　それでもいいなら　そういう方法はある
具体的には…そうだね
Specifically you would have to... How do I put this...
Suck the life out of Heart-Under-Blade until the very last moment, Araragi.
阿良々木くんは　ぎりぎりのところまでハートアンダーブレードを殺す
She would lose almost all her vampiric skills and characteristics.
吸血鬼としての特性とスキルをほとんど奪い取る　死なない程度に
On the brink of death she would become something that is even less Heart-Under-Blade than her prior forms.
ハートアンダーブレードはハートアンダーブレードとして
前以上に瀕死の状態になってもらう
She would be a husk, with no shadow, no form, and not even a name left to her.
影も形も元も子もなく　名前さえも残らないほどに
We'd have her assume an existence of a pseudo-vampire mimicking a human.
吸血鬼擬きの人間の如き存在になってもらう
どれだけお腹が減っても人間は食べられない　そんな存在に
No matter how much she hungered, she would be unable to eat any humans.
A pitiful existence such as that.
And, as for you, Araragi,
you wouldn't become human either.
そして　阿良々木くんもそれでは人間に戻れない
However, you would be very close to human.
けれど　擦れ擦れまでは戻れる
Araragi, you would be a pseudo-human mimicking a vampire.
阿良々木くんには人間擬きの吸血鬼の如き存在になってもらう
Strictly speaking, you couldn't be classified as human, but you would be far away from vampirism.
厳密には人間と言えないけれど　だけど吸血鬼からは限りなく遠い
You would assume that sort of half-baked existence.
そんな中途半端な存在になってもらう
It'd suit you well.
お似合いだね
However, if settled like that, Heart-Under-Blade, unable to procure nutrients, would starve to death.
ただし…この始末だと
阿良々木くんはともかく
ハートアンダーブレードは栄養が足らずに餓死してしまうからね
The only source of nourishment left to Heart-Under-Blade,
ハートアンダーブレードを唯一生かし続けられる栄養素は
in her diminished state, would be the blood flowing in your neck, Araragi.
彼女をそんな下等な存在に落とした君の血肉だけだ
You would have to support Heart-Under-Blade for the rest of your life,
君は残り一生をハートアンダーブレードに捧げなければならないし
and Heart-Under-Blade would be tied to you for the rest of her life.
ハートアンダーブレードは残りの一生　ずっと君に寄り添わなくてはならない
So, that means, us humans would—
じゃあ　つまり私たち人間は…
That's right.  The humans would abandon their extermination
そう　吸血鬼という危険な存在の退治を諦める
of these vampires.
However, a certain risk would remain.
つまり　そういうリスクを残す
Heart-Under-Blade and Araragi could possibly return to vampirism
ハートアンダーブレードと阿良々木くんが吸血鬼に戻り
and start eating humans. That would be an ever-present risk, one which could not be ignored.
人を食べるかもしれないという危険度を
決して無視できない程度に残す
ふ…ふざけたことを吐かすな　小僧
Stop spouting such nonsense, you brat!
I do not wish to live on in such a pitiful condition!
そ…そんな状態になってまで生き延びたいなどとわしは思わん
わ…わしは死ぬ
I will die! Let me die for his sake!
こやつのために死なせてくれ
Kill me! Hurry up and put an end to me!
殺せ　殺せ　さっさと殺せ
I do not wish to live any longer!
わしは生きたいとは思っていない
Like I said, you'd be dealing with some dissatisfaction.
だから不幸になってもらうんだって
君の望みは叶わない
Your desires would not come to fruition.
And besides, the one who gets to decide is Araragi.
尤も　決めるのは阿良々木くんだけど
Servant!
従僕
Dear servant... Servant of mine...
Dear servant...
従僕
Even so, I want you to live.
それでも　僕は…
お前に生きて欲しいと思うんだ
I... I beg of you.
た…頼む…お願いじゃ
Please! Please be so kind as to kill me.
どうか…どうかわしを殺してくれ
わしを殺して　どうか人間に戻ってくれ　助けると思って
Please kill me and regain your humanity.
Think of it as saving me once again.
I'm sorry, Kiss-shot.
ごめんな　キスショット
I can't save you.
僕はお前を助けない
August 8th
Your wounds...
傷
Huh?
They left scars.
傷　残ったんだね
So about how vampiric is your body now that it's all done?
結局　阿良々木くんの体にはどれくらいの吸血鬼性が残ったの？
まあ　治癒力がそれなりに上がってはいるようだな
It seems I heal a bit quicker now.
When I brush my teeth, I don't think my gums can even bleed.
歯を磨いても歯茎から血が出にくくなった気がする
地味な
That's boring.
That's the sum of it.
そんなとこだ
If I take a positive outlook, I did manage to restore my humanity.
ポジティブな見方をするなら
一応は人間に戻れはしたが　それなりに後遺症が残ったってところだな
However, in exchange for that, there are after-effects.
ふん…後遺症ね
After-effects, eh?
まあ　今の僕が人間だとしても
Well, if I consider myself as a human now,
out here walking under the sun as I am,
こうして太陽の下に出られるってだけで
how I view the world has changed considerably.
随分と世界が変わった気がするよ
That's very positive.
前向きだね
Heya. You're quite late, Araragi. We were getting impatient.
やぁ　遅かったね阿良々木くん　待ち兼ねたよ
I really am...
本当…
I'm really sorry.
本当にごめんな
If you ever feel like killing me, you can do so whenever you like.
殺したくなったら　いつでも殺していいから
I don't think that's a very righteous outcome, though.
それもまた　正しいことだとは思わないけどね
You can probably call this human egotism.
人間の身勝手とでも言うのかな
What you remember of a vampire eating someone,
君が吸血鬼の人食いに嫌悪を覚えたのは
if I had to make a comparison, is like the disillusionment of watching a cute cat devour a live mouse.
言ってみれば
可愛らしい猫ちゃんが鼠を食べているシーンを見て幻滅するのと同じだよ
And here you are, having chosen to keep your own little vampire like a pet.
そして君は　言わばペットとして吸血鬼を飼うことを選んだんだ
You've dulled its fangs, pulled out its claws,
牙を削って爪を抜いて喉を潰して去勢して…ね
crushed its throat and neutered it,
right?
You, who was once treated as a pet, are getting back at your former master by treating her as one.
ペット扱いされた君が主人をペット扱いし返した
When you think about it like that, it's not a very moving tale, is it?
そう考えると　さして美談でもないな
But still, I'll be here to help if the need arises.
でもまあ　その時は僕が何とかしてあげるから
If you ever grow tired of your current state, come let me know at any time.
そんな自分に嫌気が差したらいつでも言ってくれよ　阿良々木くん
There's no way I'll grow tired of it.
嫌になることなんてないよ
I'm doing it because it pleases me, after all.
好きでやってることなんだから
Then why don't you just do as you please?
じゃあ　好きにしたら？
We, who hurt each other so terribly,
will sit here licking each other's wounds.
互いに傷付け合った僕たちは　その傷を舐め合う
We damaged goods will each seek the other out in comfort.
傷物になった僕たちは　互いに互いを求め合う
If you are to die tomorrow,
I'm fine with my life ending then as well.
お前が明日死ぬのなら僕の命は明日まででいい
But if you want to live for me for one more day,
I'll go on living with you today as well.
お前が今日を生きてくれるなら　僕もまた今日を生きていこう
And thus begins a tale of kindred bound by their scars.
そして傷物たちの物語が始まる
Soaked in red and written in black,
赤く濡れて黒く乾いた　血の物語
a story of blood.
One of which I'll never speak.
決して癒えない　僕たちの大事な傷の物語
Our very own, precious as it is, story of scars.
And I have no intention
僕はそれを誰にも語ることはない
of reciting it to anyone.
A star, and you
Étoile, et toi
And you, and me
Et toi, et moi
The world is beautiful
Le monde est beau
And you are my world
Vous êtes le monde
A star, and you
Étoile, et toi
And you, and me
Et toi, et moi
All that I see
Tout ce que je vois
And all that I feel
Tout ce que je ressens
You are my universe
Tu es mon univers
I want to hear you call my name
Je veux vous entendre appeler mon nom
I want to feel your presence in my arms
Je peux te sentir dans mes bras
And for this love to last for eternity
Et c'est l'amour qui va durer pour toujours
A star, and you
Étoile, et toi
And you, and me
Et toi, et moi
You are my universe
Tu es mon univers
I want to hear you call my name
Je veux vous entendre appeler mon nom
I want to feel your presence in my arms
Je peux te sentir dans mes bras
Yes, this love will last for eternity
Oui c'est l'amour qui va durer pour toujours
A star, and you
Étoile, et toi
And you, and me
Et toi, et moi
You are my universe
Tu es mon univers